in this exercise we are asked to
use the modulo operator integer division
or both to take a four digit number
and find the digit in the thousands
hundreds
tens and ones place so let's begin with
the thousands place
i'll initialize a local variable
thousands
and we need a four digit number for this
exercise
let's use the number 4936
finding the digit in the thousands place
for a four digit number
is pretty simple using integer division
we'll simply divide by a thousand and
the return value of that integer
division will be four
to see that
let's use string interpolation
and output that result i'll hop over to
the command line
and run our file
as expected the return value of that
operation was four
now that we've successfully found the
digit in the thousands place
let's move on to the hundreds place
for the rest of this exercise the modulo
operator is going to come in handy
let's move back over to our command line
and hop into irb to see how this works
we saw that using integer division to
divide
4936 by 1000
returned 4. the modulo operator
returns the remainder
in this case that's 936.
once we have this three-digit number
it's easy to isolate the digit in the
hundreds place
with integer division again we'll divide
936 by 100 and return
9.
so let's go back to our text editor
we'll use the modulo operator to get the
remainder of
dividing 4936 by 1000
and divide that by one hundred
and we expect that the integer
referenced by the variable hundreds will
be
nine let's hop over to the command line
and we see nine as we were expecting
now let's move on to isolating the digit
in the tens place
we'll follow a similar process here as
we did
for finding the digit in the hundreds
place
however this time we need the remainder
of dividing
the original number by 100
and we expect that the return of this
operation will be 36
so we'll use integer division to divide
that by 10
and now we expect that the local
variable tens
references three
and it does
so we're almost finished our last step
is to isolate the digit in the ones
place
and again this will be very similar to
what we just did to isolate the three
from the tens place
this time we need the remainder of
dividing our original four digit number
by ten we expect that this
operation alone will return the last
digit in the number
six and therefore we don't need to
perform
any additional integer division like we
did for the previous steps
we run our file and we see that we've
successfully
isolated 6 as the digit in the ones
place
integer division and the modulo operator
are important tools for working with
integers
you